<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Azam Rahman</title>
    <subtitle>Personal blog — notes on software, systems, and life.</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://azamrahman.com/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://azamrahman.com"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://azamrahman.com/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>The Journey Thus Far</title>
        <published>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-09-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://azamrahman.com/blog/20250918-mixplate-ai-one-year-one-app-one-big-pivot/"/>
        <id>https://azamrahman.com/blog/20250918-mixplate-ai-one-year-one-app-one-big-pivot/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://azamrahman.com/blog/20250918-mixplate-ai-one-year-one-app-one-big-pivot/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-first-bet-an-app-to-help&quot;&gt;The First Bet: An App to Help&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back in early 2024, my mission was simple: help small businesses with their marketing. In a country like brunei there are so many people trying to start side businesses, doing freelance work, or starting up an ecommerce store, but because marketing isn&#x27;t their forte they were struggling to be consistent...&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, I built a mobile app. It had AI-powered content generation, a post scheduler, and an AI chat assistant for ideation, and the features I thought a small business would need to &quot;do&quot; their marketing more efficiently. Leading a team of 2 developers and 1 designer, After months of work, it launched on the &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;apps.apple.com&#x2F;us&#x2F;app&#x2F;mixplate-ai&#x2F;id6482852564&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;&#x2F;a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https:&#x2F;&#x2F;play.google.com&#x2F;store&#x2F;apps&#x2F;details?id=com.felsent.mixplate_ai_frontend&quot;&gt;Google Play&lt;&#x2F;a&gt;.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-whispers-of-a-pivot&quot;&gt;The Whispers of a Pivot&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then came the feedback. I talked to users, friends, and mentors. A consistent theme emerged: the app helped with the how of marketing—how to schedule a post, how to write a caption—but their real, burning pain wasn&#x27;t the how. It was the what and the why.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;What should I actually be posting this week?&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;Why is my competitor growing faster than me?&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&quot;I&#x27;m posting consistently, but is any of this actually working?&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out that these strategic questions were the greatest reason for the lack of clarity in many businessowners&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-new-bet-from-tool-to-ai-strategist&quot;&gt;The New Bet: From Tool to AI Strategist&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I decided to evolve Mixplate from a simple &quot;AI social media tool&quot; into an &quot;AI Marketing Strategist &amp;amp; Analyst.&quot;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new mission is not just to help you do marketing, but to give you the strategic direction to do the right marketing. The core is a data engine that analyzes your performance against direct competitors and surfaces a single, non-obvious, deeply actionable insight every week. It’s designed to be the AI strategist you can’t afford to hire—telling you exactly where the biggest opportunity is and what to do about it.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a data product, delivered in a simple, beautiful report. Early feedback from the first pilot users has been electrifying.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-i-m-building-this-in-public&quot;&gt;Why I&#x27;m Building This in Public&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#x27;ve decided to share this journey—the wins and the messy middle—for a few key reasons:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accountability&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: Putting goals and progress out in the open creates a powerful forcing function. It’s a promise to myself, my users, and my followers that I will keep moving forward.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Feedback Loop&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The smartest people I know aren&#x27;t on my payroll; they&#x27;re on the internet. By sharing what I&#x27;m building, I open myself up to feedback, critiques, and ideas that will make the product better.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Find My People&lt;&#x2F;strong&gt;: The founder journey can be lonely. Building in public connects me with other builders, makers, and potential customers who resonate with this mission. If this story sounds familiar, I&#x27;d love to hear from you.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;closing&quot;&gt;Closing&lt;&#x2F;h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Life&#x27;s full of unknowns, maybe what I&#x27;m building today will be something completely different tomorrow. But the end goal stays the same: building something to empower founder-led brands everywhere.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
</content>
        
    </entry>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Hello, world</title>
        <published>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-09-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            
              Unknown
            
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://azamrahman.com/blog/20250917-hello-world/"/>
        <id>https://azamrahman.com/blog/20250917-hello-world/</id>
        
        <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hi, I’m starting my blog using Zola and the Duckquill theme. This post is just a quick “hello” and a smoke test that everything is wired correctly.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;</summary>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
